<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mirko Caserta</title>
    <link>https://mirkocaserta.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mirko Caserta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 18:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mirkocaserta.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>🇮🇹 Pensa alle tue orecchie come fossero occhi</title>
      <link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2018/10/pensa-alle-tue-orecchie-come-fossero-occhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 18:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2018/10/pensa-alle-tue-orecchie-come-fossero-occhi/</guid>
      <description>Metafisica dei Suoni Se la musica è l’arte dei suoni, l’ear training è l&amp;rsquo;allenamento dell&amp;rsquo;orecchio musicale. Cosa si intende con orecchio musicale? L&amp;rsquo;udito ha un aspetto passivo più ovvio che consiste nella capacità di riconoscere i suoni, ma ha anche un aspetto attivo in cui il musicista improvvisa una frase ed è istantaneamente in grado di produrla sul proprio strumento.
Ma di questo parleremo più avanti. Per ora torniamo al suono.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🇮🇹 Kind of papera che non galleggia</title>
      <link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2018/10/kind-of-papera-che-non-galleggia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2018/10/kind-of-papera-che-non-galleggia/</guid>
      <description>«In principio era il verbo.»
«Ah, io credevo il soggetto. Ma infatti, se senti il Maestro Yoda&amp;hellip;»
«Caserta, fai poco lo spiritoso che vojo vedè come ve la cavate cor riscaldamento globale.»
«Eh vabbè, moriremo tutti, che vuoi che sia? Mica sarebbe la prima volta.»
(a bassa voce): &amp;ldquo;Questo moo mettete nel terzo girone.»
«Guarda che t&amp;rsquo;ho sentito, sa? Al terzo girone1 so&#39; tutti amici miei. Come niente t&amp;rsquo;arrivo in finale e vinco ai rigori.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🇺🇸 An Introduction to Time Representation, Serialization and Management in Software</title>
      <link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2013/04/an-introduction-to-time-representation-serialization-and-management-in-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2013/04/an-introduction-to-time-representation-serialization-and-management-in-software/</guid>
      <description>Most issues in software development usually arise from poor, inconsistent knowledge of the domain at hand. A topic apparently as simple as time representation, serialization and management can easily cause a number of problems both to the neophyte and to the experienced programmer.
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll see that there&amp;rsquo;s no need to be a Time Lord to grasp the very simple few concepts needed not to incur into time management hell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mirkocaserta.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer based in Rome, Italy. I primarily dabble in enterprise java backends, although I&amp;rsquo;m not religious about programming languages, frameworks, platforms and architectures as I like to live on the bleeding edge and basically be a curious nerd about practically too many fields in human knowledge.
I also have a past as an amateur jazz musician that might creep out from time to time in my posts here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
